准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
垃圾深处
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
众生皆在我之下
Everyone is beneath me
又怎么了
What now?
你们这些小丑能不能安静点
Will you clowns be quiet?
我还要冥想呢
I am trying to meditate
我的老天啊  我们太吵了吗
Oh my stars, were we too loud?
考虑一下我们有多难堪
Imagine our embarrassment
这
The--
这垃圾就得倒垃圾车  别倒我家草坪
The trash goes in the truck, not on my lawn
这垃圾你们该倒哪倒哪去
Just put the garbage where it's supposed to go
我们会该倒哪倒哪去的
We'll put it exactly where it's supposed to go
我的屋顶
My roof
运气真臭
Well, this stinks
臭了六个月之后
蟹堡王
快啊
Come on
一份蟹黄堡打包外带马上来  先生
That's one Krabby Patty to go coming right up, sir
上菜了
Order up
用餐愉快  先生
Enjoy your order, sir
下一个
Next
我累坏了
I'm exhausted
我一直在想  等我醒过来
I keep thinking I'm gonna wake up
又要面对午餐高峰期
back in the lunch rush
我已经休息五分钟了
I've been on my break for five minutes
满脑子想的却只有下一单
and all I can think about is getting my next order
你干嘛躺在地上  小子
Why are you on the floor, lad?
抱歉  蟹老板
Sorry, Mr. Krabs
只是在休息而已
just taking a break
休息
Break?
你什么时候开始休息的
Since when did you start taking breaks?
自从我开始干我自己的工作
Since I started doing both my job
又要兼顾章鱼哥的工作就这样了
and Squidward's at the same time
章鱼哥今天没出现吗
Squidward didn't show up today?
章鱼哥已经六个月没来上班了
Squidward hasn't come to work in six months
真的吗
Really?
我实在跟不上速度了  蟹老板
I just can't keep up the pace, Mr. Krabs
我得去他家看看他有没有事
I'll go to his house to see if he's okay
慢着  小子
Whoa there, laddie
你身上可是担着两份工作
you have two jobs to cover
等下班了才可以去看章鱼哥
You can go visit Squidward when you're off the clock
你确定他在里面吗
You sure he's in there?
看看他的信箱
Look at his mailbox
还有他家传出来的臭味
And that smell coming from his house
实在
It's
不寻常
unusual
还以为是我的味道
I thought it was me
我们真的应该检查下他的情况
We really should check up on him
好啊  反正我闲着没事干
Sure, I got nothing better to do
章鱼哥
Squidward?
你在家吗
Are you home?
章鱼哥把这地方搞得乱七八糟的
Squidward's really let the place go
你们令我想起了
You remind me
一位海绵宝宝和一位派大星
of a SpongeBob and a Patrick
我在外面的世界认识了他们
I knew in the outer world
海霸王
Bubble Bass
你在这里干嘛
What are you doing here?
有时候  潜入垃圾堆能找到收藏品
Sometimes you dumpster dive and find collectibles
其他时候  下场都是迷失在
other times you end up lost
一个无穷无尽的垃圾世界里
in an un-ending trash world
不错
Neat
有看到章鱼哥吗
Have you seen Squidward?
我不认识什么章鱼哥
I don't know any Squidward
但你们可以问尊者
but you could ask the Exalted One
谁啊
Who now?
但愿我能用言语形容
I only wish I had the words
我无足轻重  就是个零蛋
I am nothing, a zero
他完美无瑕  是垃圾之爵
He's perfection, the duke of debris
你知不知道他在哪
Do you know where he is or not?
好吧
Fine
往那边走
Go that way
虽然这场旅途漫长又凶险
It is a long and treacherous journey
但我们仍然继续前行
But we press on
垃圾的沼气四处弥漫
Garbage gas is everywhere
似乎还会害人变笨
and it seems to be making people silly
抱歉打扰你旁白了
Sorry to interrupt your narrating
我得上个厕所
but I gotta use the can
海绵宝宝
Hey, SpongeBob
能把那边那本杂志递给我吗
could you hand me that magazine over there?
我可能得拉一阵子
This might take a while
拿去  派大星
Here you go, Patrick
太强了  兄弟
Righteous, dude
派大星  你看
Patrick, look
有个深不见底的裂谷
It's a bottomless chasm
跳
Jump
要怎么跨过去
How are we going to cross that?
看来章鱼哥只好失踪一辈子了
Yeah, I guess Squidward's lost forever
我们回家吧
Let's go home
海胆在打牌吗
Urchins play cards?
不止是牌
Not just cards
还是桥牌
Bridge
你想的跟我一样吗
Are you thinking what I'm thinking?
对
Yeah
小三明治
Tiny sandwiches
不对
No
跟我来
Follow my lead
这边有什么呢
Well, what do we have here?
海绵宝宝快看
Look, SpongeBob
这边有局纸牌友谊赛
a friendly card game is right here
天啊  我好爱打桥牌
Oh boy, do I love to play bridge
还有没有位置给给我们俩呆
You guys got room for two mor--
我的海神王啊
Sweet Neptune
有头翼龙
A pterodactyl
快跑
Run
我拿到三明治了
I got the sandwiches
我拿到牌了
And I got the cards
桥牌要怎么帮得上忙
How are bridge cards gonna help?
可以建造一座悬置不信的大桥
By building a suspension of disbelief bridge
[ 悬置不信：欣赏作品时暂时不去质疑真实性 ]
快跑
Run
没打中我
Missed me
尊者的居所
"The Exalted One's lair
禁止入内
Stay out"
你们虽然坚持到了这里
You made it this far
但还是必须通过前方的陷阱
but you still must pass the booby traps up ahead
看着像某种袜子管道
Looks like some sort of tube of socks
还是臭袜子
Stinky socks
小心
Careful
慢慢来
Easy does it
刮风了
Breeze
好臭的味
That smell
这湖肯定是纯垃圾水
This lagoon must be pure garbage juice
千万不要被它碰
so don't let it touch--
章鱼哥应该就在这里了
I think this is where Squidward is
为什么会这么说
What makes you say that?
你们说的可是尊者
You speak of the Exalted One
垃圾王公
the raja of rubbish
还是
the--
章鱼哥
Squidward
他现在可是超越了章鱼哥的存在
He is beyond Squidward now
他是超越了消费与分解循环的伟人
He is a great man who has risen above
the cycle of consuming and discarding
他一直在垃圾深处等候着
He has been waiting in the heart of garbage
请进
Enter
好吧
Okay
这里面的垃圾沼气也太难闻了
The garbage gas is really stinky in here
害得我头晕目眩
It's making me dizzy
你呢
You?
没比平常晕多少
No more than usual
章鱼哥
Squidward?
人的价值是什么
What is the value of a man?
腌椰菜的价格有多少
What is the price of a pickle?
你就慢慢去琢磨
While you ponder that, man
我要吹点炫酷的曲调
I'm going to play something sick-el
派大星快看  大家都很爱听
Look, Patrick, everyone is into it
沼气影响了他的心智
The gas has affected his mind
章鱼哥
Squidward
是我海绵宝宝啊
It's SpongeBob
我是来救你出去的
I've come to get you out of here
你就只是个打杂的
You're nothing but an errand boy
不对  他是个做蟹黄堡的
No, he's a patty laddie
不用谢
You're welcome
做蟹黄堡的
Patty laddie?
对  是蟹堡王那个做蟹黄堡的
Yeah, a patty laddie from the Krusty Krab
我们可是同事啊
We worked there together
蟹堡王
The Krusty Krab?
我开始想起来了
I'm beginning to remember
对
Yes
我恨我的工作
I hated my job
我跟派大星还是你邻居
And Patrick and I are your neighbors
对
Yes
我还恨我的邻居
I hated my neighbors too
我想起来了
I remember
欢迎回家  章鱼哥
Welcome home, Squidward
我家为什么全是垃圾
Why is my home filled with garbage?
那什么臭味啊
And what is that gassy smell?
我家全废了
My place is ruined
用光照一下就能看清这片废墟了
You can see the ruin better in the light
还好我带了这个点满蜡烛的烛台
Good thing I brought this fully lit candelabra
别别别
No, no, no
派大星  有沼气啊
Patrick, the gas
至少垃圾再也没在你家里面了
At least the garbage isn't in your house anymore
史上最烂垃圾邪教
Worst garbage cult ever
我的家
My house
再见了  海绵宝宝
Well, goodbye, SpongeBob
再见  章鱼哥
Goodbye, Squidward
再见  派大星
Goodbye, Patrick
明天上班见
See you at work tomorrow
尊者
Exalted One
请勿打扰
手办痞老板
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
蟹堡王
快来快来
Hurry, hurry
来买特别款收藏品蟹黄堡
Get your collectible special edition Krabby Patty
特别款
腌椰菜堡
多加腌椰菜
with extra pickles
欲购从速
Act now
数量有限
Supplies are limited
给我来一个
Give me one
我要六个
I want six
都借过
Coming through
别挡路
Outta my way
需要点餐吗
May I take your order?
要
Yes
我呢  是个著名的胡子学家
I am, uh, a prominent mustache-ologist
对  就这样
Yes, that's it
我想要来个特别款的蟹黄堡
And I would like a special edition Krabby Patty
胡子学家是吧
Mustache-ologist, huh?
来了个真的胡子专家
A real mustache expert
我有好多问题想请教
I have so many questions
你比较喜欢润须蜡还是胡须护理油
Do you prefer mustache wax or beard oil?
这就有点难回答了
That's a tough one
胡须护理油
Beard oil?
大家都知道润须蜡才更好用
Everyone knows mustache wax is superior
不然你以为我这卷须是怎么长的
How else do you think I got these whiskery curls
这个所谓的专家完全就不懂胡子
This so-called expert
doesn't know a thing about mustaches
痞老板
Plankton
怪不得会闻到有什么绿玩意臭臭的
I thought I smelled something green and stinky
假胡子不错
Nice fake mustache
那胡子可是我花了六个月长出来的
I spent six months growing that mustache
蟹黄堡永远也到不了手了
I'll never get a Krabby Patty
它又不会就这么走出餐厅
It's not like it's gonna just walk out of the restaurant
端在银盘子上白白送我
on a silver platter
我的特别款蟹黄堡收藏又多了个精品
Another excellent addition to my collection
of special edition Krabby Patties
被打脸了
I stand corrected
偷到蟹黄堡的机会终于来了
This is my chance to finally get a patty
而且还没那个该死的老螃蟹碍事
without that blasted Krabs getting in my way
快来  凯伦
Come on, Karen
抱歉  亲爱的
Sorry, sweetie
我一天最多只能偷一次蟹黄堡
but I have a one-caper-a-day maximum
我要回家整理自己的硬盘碎片
I'm going home to defrag my hard drive
看来我只能自个搭车了
I guess I'll have to hitch my own ride
老妈
Mother
有事就到地下室找我
I'll be in the basement
你在我收藏家小金库一定会平平安安
You'll be nice and safe in my secure collector's vault
该把你放哪呢
Now where should I put you
我的小小宝贝蟹黄堡
my precious little patty?
就让它挨着我的爱聊堡
I'll place it next to my Chatty
肥肥堡和顽童堡吧
Fatty, and Bratty Patties
海霸王  快上来帮我搓脚
Bubble Bass, get up here and rub my tootsies
好  老妈
Yes, Mother
终于能偷到一个蟹黄堡了
I'll finally obtain a Krabby Patty
多亏有那个白痴阿宅
thanks to that goofy geek
什么动静
What was that noise?
不能让那个土肥圆发现我
Can't let that bulbous buffoon find me
给我现身  可恶的入侵者
Show yourself, foul intruder
我的特别款邪恶臭蛞蝓加超级黏液
My special edition Sinister Slug with super slime
我得重新把包装封好
I'll have to re-seal the package
正好
Perfect
就好像全新未拆封的一样
Like it was never opened
别再惹出麻烦来了
Now don't go causing any more trouble
再见了  我的小可爱们
I'll see you soon, my lovelies
海霸王
Bubble Bass
我的润足霜都快凉了
My foot butter is getting cold
现在来取我的蟹黄堡
Now to get my Krabby Patty
我可能碰上问题了
I may have a problem
凯伦肯定会发现我不见了
Well, I'm sure Karen will notice that I'm gone
然后过来找我
and come find me
我都快饿死了
I'm getting hungry
还是比海霸糊好吃
Well, it still tastes better than chum
几周后
海之霸
硬盘碎片彻底整理干净最爽了
Nothing beats a thorough defragging
对吧  痞老板
eh, Plankton?
痞老板
Plankton?
他哪去了
Where is he?
最好检查下他平常会去的老地方
I'd better check the usual spots
嗨  凯伦
Hi, Karen
又来这里偷秘方吗
Here to steal the secret formula again?
没  我下班了
Nah, I'm off the clock
其实我只是在找痞老板
Just looking for Plankton actually
你有看到他吗
Have you seen him?
天啊
Golly
我好几周都没看到他了
I haven't seen him in weeks
不过还是先检查下抓痞老板的陷阱
But let's check all the Plankton traps
以防万一
just in case
不在这
Not here
空的
Empty
也不在这
Not here either
他会躲在哪呢
Where could he be hiding?
你放心  凯伦
Don't you worry, Karen
我一定会帮你追踪到痞老板
I'll help you track Plankton down
追踪他吗
Track him?
有了
That's it
我给痞老板安装了个追踪芯片
I installed a tracking chip on Plankton
以防他被冲进下水道
in case he got washed down the drain
已经不止一次了
again
痞老板的信号是从那里传来的
Plankton's signal is coming from that way
最后一点黏液也吃完了
That's the last of the goo
看来只能吃自己的四肢了
Guess I'll move on to my limbs
我一定要逃出去
I've got to get out of here
等下  可以用这东西烧出一个洞
Hold on, I can use this to burn a hole
大到可以让我逃出这个古怪玩具监狱
big enough to get out of this kooky toy prison
着火了
Fire?
我的邪恶臭蛞蝓玩具
My Sinister Slug toy
可你是怎么跑到这下面来的
But how did you get down here?
老妈一定又在做有氧运动了
Mother must have been practicing her aerobics again
多半是我的官方正版
Maybe my official
企鹅男孩祛痘霜到了
Barnacle Boy acne cream has arrived
原来是你们俩啊
It's you two
太失望了
How disappointing
滚开
Go away
你好  海霸王
Hello, Bubble Bass
痞老板在这吗
is Plankton here?
谁啊
Who?
绿色矮个  有股海霸糊味
Short, green, smells like chum
我才不跟这种肮脏的家伙一起混
I do not associate with such sordid individuals
你们不介意的话
Now, if you don't mind
可能是你的追踪装置坏掉了
Maybe your tracker's on the blink
他就在里面没错
He's in there
咱们晚点再来侦察一下
Let's come back later for a little reconnaissance
把我反锁起来是吧
Lock me away, will ya?
等我给这些塑料玩意重新接线
Once I rewire these plastic doodads
改装成万能遥控器
into a universal remote
我就能控制这些玩具  击倒那个宅男
I'll take over these toys, knock that nerd out
拿到蟹黄堡
grab the Krabby Patty
最后逃出去
and escape
好
Yes
当晚的晚些时候
好  计划如下
Okay, here's the plan:
你关掉监控
While you disable the surveillance cameras
我逆向破解进门的密码
I'll reverse engineer the access codes
用我的磁谐振器
and use my magnetic resonator
解锁安全系数极高的插销锁
to unlock the high security deadbolt locks
这扇窗户没锁
This window's unlocked
爬窗户也行
Or we could use the window
他一定就在里面
He must be in there
这一定是某种脸部识别扫描器
This must be some kind of facial recognition scanner
这玩意应该不是刷脸的
I don't think those are the right kind of cheeks
这扫描器是刷屁股的
It's a booty-metric scanner
得找海霸王才打得开
We'll need Bubble Bass to open it
老妈
Mother
有事就到地下室找我
I'll be in the basement
我要整理我的美人鱼战士收藏品
organizing my Mermaid Man memorabilia
你咋不去整理简历
Why don't you organize your resume
找个班上
and get a job?
老妈
Mother
得躲起来
We need to hide
躲那
Over there
只能等他睡着了再行动
We'll have to wait until he falls asleep
我应该可以稍微加速一下
I think I can speed things up a little
三重色氨酸火鸡蟹黄堡
A triple tryptophan turkey Krabby Patty
感恩节限定
A Thanksgiving exclusive
老妈教过我不要对礼物吹毛求疵
Mother told me never look a gift patty in the buns
吃完火鸡堡就没有一个不晕过去的
No one is immune to the ol' post-turkey patty food coma
受死吧  你这臭白痴
Time to meet your doom, you smelly simpleton
谢尔顿痞老板  马上给我从那里下来
Sheldon J. Plankton, you come down
from there this instant
凯伦
Karen?
抱歉刚刚朝你发射导弹  亲爱的
Sorry about the missiles, sweetie pie
这是在吵什么吵
What is all that racket?
又见面了
Hello again
玩具贼
Toy thieves
启动终极封锁程序
Activate ultimate lockdown protocol
恐慌
这些泡沫塑料能让我地下室所有东西
These packing peanuts will preserve
everything in my basement
保持九九新的状态
in mint condition
更何况我们
Even us
海霸王
Bubble Bass
晚餐时间到了
It's dinner time
快上楼做饭
So get up here and start cooking
他现在又在乱搞什么玩意
What nonsense is he up to now?
你又在里面玩玩具了吗
Are you playing with your toys in there?
没  老妈
No, Mother
快放我出去啊
Now get me out of here
不行
Oh no
就用这个让你跟你朋友长长记性
Let this be a lesson to you and your little friends
不准在家里面鬼混
not to horse around in the house
好  老妈
Yes, Mother
有个蟹黄堡
A Krabby Patty
不要
No
老妈
Mother